Paul Thompson, BA Albuquerque, New Mexico

findingfocus.dev • github.com/findingfocus • paul@findingfocus.dev • (505) 331-0495

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Software developer with over five years of experience in languages including JavaScript, C, and Python. Passionate about creating software solutions, specializing in prototyping interactive experiences. Analytical, professional, and highly motivated to learn and collaborate within a digital engineering ecosystem.

SKILLS

- Frontend: React, Next.js, Node.js, Tailwind, Svelte
- Backend: Express, Nginx, Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, C, Lua, Python
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Docker, Ubuntu, Nvim, Love2d, Slack, Asana, RESTful APIs, Scrum Methodologies

PROJECTS

No Concessions - (Full-Stack Web Application) noconcessions.xyz | Github

- Collaborated with a team of 4 developers to design, implement, and deploy a web application for movie recommendations based on past rating history.
- Constructed frontend with React, Next.js, Node.js, and Tailwind for a mobile responsive application, and a backend using Express and PostgreSQL for database management.
- Implemented API calls using RESTful endpoints to retrieve movie data from themoviedb.org.
- Our application allows users to register an account and track movie recommendations in a watchlist. My favorite page I designed allows users to rate each movie with a simple tap or a click and drag gesture.

Tak: A Beautiful Game - (Two player digital board game) Github

- My capstone project for Harvard's CS50x course. I built a digital version of a board game where two
 players compete to win the best of three games.
- Game prototyped and programmed in the Love2d game engine using Lua.
- The most challenging part of this project was how to conceptualize a three dimensional board game converted into two dimensions, and the adaptive rendering I needed to illustrate depth-based mechanics. I added a release with executable builds for Windows, MacOS, as well as Linux.

Programming Portfolio – findingfocus.xyz

- My portfolio website was built to showcase my creativity as a programmer.
- I programmed my mobile responsive website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Tailwind.
- The site hosts source code for my projects and playable demos that work both on desktop and mobile.
- I am most proud of the executable releases I added for each game. I included releases for Windows, Mac and Linux operating systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Finding Focus Productions

Owner/Operator | 2014 - Present

- Contract with organizations and individuals to design and produce high-quality multimedia content.
- Establish relationships with the Albuquerque community through multimedia services including promotional material, wedding videos, website design, interviews, music videos, and live events.
- Utilize software to create and maintain multimedia projects (Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Audition, Adobe Photoshop, Davinci Resolve, Canto, Asana).

Center for Action and Contemplation

Digital Imaging Technician/Video Editor | July 2018 – August 2020

- Prepared all film gear for productions, and used cinema cameras with professional audio equipment to record educational material.
- Created and maintained the post-production workflow for all video projects.
- Contributed strategically to the vast media library system.
- Worked with the Creative Director on innovative art experiences and experimental video projects.

BeWellNM

Multimedia Content Producer | January 2014 - May 2014

- Wrote, shot, and edited multiple informational videos for the New Mexico Health Insurance program.
- Produced original commercials targeting younger demographics and managed the Google AdWords campaigns to promote the videos.
- Recommended and implemented a production workflow to meet strict deadlines.

New Mexico Department of Workforce Solutions

Multimedia Content Producer | September 2012 – October 2014

- Shot and edited multiple informational videos for the www.dws.state.nm.us website.
- Created engaging videos incorporating music and graphics to enhance the organization's image.
- Carefully arranged content to maintain brand consistency, ensuring approval by board members.

TNT Development

Community Navigator for Neurodivergent Youth | January 2017 – Present

- Weekly mentorship of a 25-year-old boy with autism to introduce him to community events and activities.
- Actively engage with life-long values associated with inclusion, compassion, and open-mindedness.
- Responsible for scheduling and overseeing partial or all-day activities including road trips.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

- Deep Dive Fullstack Bootcamp, Central New Mexico Community College | 2024
- Bachelor of Arts in Film & Digital Arts | August 2012 December 2016
- CS50x: CS50's Introduction to Computer Science Verified Certificate of Completion from HarvardX
- FAA Aeronautical Knowledge Test for Part 107 Unmanned Aircraft General Small (UAG)